## Diky Arga Anggara

Front-end Developer - Bukalapak.com

Email : dikyarga.id@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dikyarga

Github : https://github.com/dikyarga

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

I'm a Full Stack JavaScript Developer, who uses React or VueJS at front-end and ExpressJS at backend (formerly using Laravel). I am also an open source enthusiast, that is why I joined and contributed to Mozilla Foundation as Mozilla Tech Speaker (formerly Firefox Student Ambassador) and Dinus Open Source Community as a leader. Current work for million of user of Bukalapak.com

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Backend: Node.js & Express, PHP & Laravel
Frontend SPA: React & Redux, VueJS & Vuex

• Mobile: React Native

• Frontend: HTML5, CSS3 (Saas or LESS), jQuery

• Versioning Control : Git

• Testing: Mocha + Chai, Nightmare, Jest

Database

SQL : MySql, Postgres, SQLiteNo Sql : MongoDB with Mongoose

• WebVR : A-Frame

• Chat Bot : API.AI, Line & Telegram Bot

• Deployment : AWS and VPS

### **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

**BukaLelang - App for online auction in Indonesia :** Try to solve the real problem about online auction in Indonesia with bleeding-edge technology like React Native and real time data transfer through Websocket using Socket.io. I was charged as a Back-End Developer at this project, who was responsible to make sure all codes were tested using TDD style and well documented.

Code: https://github.com/BukaLelang/bukalelang-backend

API documentation: http://api.bukalelang.id/docs/

Matory - Mall Directory Chat-Bot - A chat bot to help people find store at malls: Combine Artificial Intelligence and Natural Language Processing and integrated with chat platform like Line and Telegram Messenger through Webhook with HTTPS protocol. Matory had 700 Line friends only in a week after launch and received more than 9K chats. I was responsible to create bot logic, deployment and integration to chat platform.

**TeaLinuxOS** - **An Operating System for Your Developing Environment**: We created an operating system to help Programmers (especially newbie programmers), to easily catch up with programming without thinking any confusing development environment, such as installing compiler, tools, configure IDE, etc. At this project, I was responsible to create some apps on top of TeaLinuxOS, like Lapor Hama, TeaLinux Studio, Modularitea, Web Redesign. I presented TeaLinuxOS at Mozilla Festival in London. User Guide: http://tealinuxos.org/dukungan/panduan

**SPGDT - Sistem Penanggulangan Gawat Darurat Terpadu :** I created a system that can help victims get quick and integrated treatment from various parties (such as Ambulance, Hospital, Police and PMI). I use Laravel and Gammu SMS Gateway to broadcast information about the accident.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp (Full-Stack Web Development). Hacktiv8 (Jakarta, Indonesia) 2017

Computer Science GPA: 3.2/4 Universitas Dian Nuswantoro (Semarang, Indonesia) 2013 - 2017

#### VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

## Mozilla Foundation as Mozilla Tech Speaker

2015 - present

Two International talk as Mozilla Tech Speaker.

- Mozilla Festival 2016 London
- FOSS ASIA 2017 Singapore

## Dinus Open Source Community as a Leader

2015 - 2016

Doscom is a open source community Dian Nuswantoro University, creator of TeaLinuxOS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# PT. Bukalapak.com

Sep 2017 - present

## Senior Front-End Developer

Turn design into desktop and mobile web for million of user in Indonesia.

MTarget.co Oct 2016 – Feb 2017

#### **Front-End Developer**

MailTarget is a sister company of GNEWS and I was also responsible to translate design from UI designer into webview.

Technology: VueJS, VueRouter, Vuex, Axios

# GNEWS - Social News Reader

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

# Front-end Developer (Intern)

I was responsible to translate design from UI designer into webview using jQuery combine Bootstrap with LESS. I was also responsible to consume data from API using Axios with help from Swagger.

Freelancer Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

Help to realize several government projects and corporate. I managed to adapt my time consistently between work and study hours.

#### **ACHIEVEMENT**

- 1 St Winner of Bukalapak Development Competition 2017 with BukaLelang App
- 1 St Tutorial contest CodePolitan X Hacktiv8 2016 Jakarta
- 2 <sup>nd</sup> Firebase Hackathon App Fest 2017 Jakarta
- 3 rd Puwadhika X AAJI Hackathon 2018 Bali
- 2 <sup>nd</sup> Mawapres (Mahasiswa Berprestasi) at Dian Nuswantoro University 2017
- 2 nd Film Documenter Dinas Pemuda & Olahraga Kabupaten Kendal 2014
- 1 St Winner of Bukalapak Internal Hackathon 2017 & 2018

## **SPEAKING EXPERIENCE**

- Mozilla Festival 2016 London, UK
- FOSS ASIA 2017 Singapore
- JSDay.id 2019 Jakarta
- Google Developer Group Meetup 2018 Bali
- Seminar Nasional E-Commerce 2018 Madura
- Hacktoberfest Contribute to Open Source 2018 Jakarta
- Release Party TeaLinuxOS X 2018 Semarang
- Workshop WebVR and WebAR 2016 2018 Malang, Semarang & Jakarta
- Workshop Vue.js 2017 Jakarta
- **Dinus Creative Forum -** 2018 Semarang
- FoxTalks by Hacktiv8 2018 Jakarta
- State Driven Interfaces Development 2020 Online
- and counting.